Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/farahserur (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

User Experience (UX) Adobe Creative Suite User Interface Design

Honors-Awards

Farah Rose Artist Success
Grant Recipient to attend Bulletproof
Biohacking Conference
Golden Key International Honour
Society

Publications

Featured Cover Artist

Farah Serur

Product Designer at Facebook Messenger

New York, New York, United States

Summary

I'm a UX Designer with a passion for visual design, and a focus on the people who need it. I execute cohesive, creative concepts that solve user problems

In a past life, I studied biological anthropology before following some dreams to become a painter. My paintings capture the unique experiences of the eccentric people I encountered. Now, instead of painting experiences, I also design them. I design tools that make interacting with technology more intuitive, effective, and aesthetically pleasing.

Experience

Facebook
Product Designer on Facebook Messenger
May 2020 - Present (3 years)
New York, United States

elphi

User Experience Designer
January 2020 - February 2020 (2 months)
New York City Metropolitan Area

Designed a borrower-facing interface for a fintech startup that streamlines the mortgage application process for both banks and borrowers

- Conducted competitive analysis, user interviews, card sorting, A/B testing, usability testing, and rapid prototyping to understand the mortgage lending marketplace
- Streamlined information architecture of the interface and task flow in order to increase conversions
- Created high fidelity mockups and a prototype to illustrate the borrower task flow

National Income Life Insurance Company Office Manager Assistant

Page 1 of 5

October 2018 - August 2019 (11 months)

New York City

• Ensure office operations and procedures are organized, providing general support to visitors and schedule meetings at the New York branch.

• Designed, implemented and maintain filing systems, and review supply requisitions, so that clerical functions are properly assigned and monitored.

ConArtist Collective
Artist In Residence
September 2018 - December 2018 (4 months)
New York City

- Utilized expertise of Adobe Software to design and create large-scale paintings exhibited in weekly showings in the Lower East side Gallery space. My work has been used for press releases featured on Artforum, an international resource for contemporary art.
- Demonstrated fine art skills in order to be accepted and uphold my position in the residency.

Dancing Girl Press
Cover Artist & Book Illustrator
August 2018 - November 2018 (4 months)
Greater New York City Area

Collaborated with published author to execute vision for a book cover.
 Utilized Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator to combine text and graphics that exceeded author's vision.

SuperEats

Photographer & Graphic Designer May 2018 - August 2018 (4 months)

New Orleans, LA

- Created, and executed visual thematic content through photoshoots at historical New Orleans landmarks.
- Captured and edited all creative content currently viewable on the company website.

INKED by dani Graphic Designer June 2017 - August 2017 (3 months) Greater New York City Area

- Provided graphic design, branding, and marketing services such as newsletters to increase sales to individuals and department stores
- Photographed and photoshopped images to increase audience to instagram posts by utilizing design skills and knowledge of new instagram algorithms.
- Increased stockists clientele by participating in consumer facing events, and reaching out and meeting with stores in New York City interested in stocking our product.

The Brooklyn Hospital Center Genetic Counseling Intern June 2017 - August 2017 (3 months) Brooklyn, NY

- Learned from a genetic counselor, the intricacy and demands of educating and counseling based on genetic dispositions.
- Met with patients to discuss family history, concerns, and address overall
 health. This process utilizes an individual's family history to determine whether
 it would behoove them to run through a genetic testing panel. Genetic testing
 can help expecting parents prepare for a healthy pregnancy or understand
 problems a couple may experience as a result of the combining of their unique
 genetic sequencing.
- I spoke with patients and collaboratively helped them understand which diseases they are prone to, based on genetic testing results and how they can eradicate these diseases preemptively.
- Utilized knowledge and graphic design skills to create a pamphlet for future patients outlining the importance of genetic counseling without a companies bias present in the dissemination of information. (Pamphlet available upon request).

Where Y'Art Content Creator & Graphic Designer June 2016 - August 2016 (3 months)

Greater New Orleans Area

- Refined artist profiles on the website through photography and through written biographies
- Photoshopped and digitally uploaded work in an artist's collection. Where Y'Art curates an online gallery where you can meet over 100 New Orleans artists, browse their work, and learn more about the artist.
- Digitally organized photos on the website by creating metadata and location tags to locate an artists work and for SEO.

Tunica-Biloxi Cultural & Educational Resource Center Language Revitalization Educator

June 2016 - July 2016 (2 months)

Marksville, LA

- Acquired Tunica language speaking and comprehension skills in order to formulate lesson plans and educate students of the Tunica-Biloxi Tribe in Louisiana.
- Engaged campers in cultural activities as a way of preserving culture and tribal practices, this included designing and creating costumes and set pieces for a student play.

Bella Magazine

Intern & Bella Blog Writer/Photographer

June 2015 - August 2015 (3 months)

Greater New York City Area

- Wrote articles on topics including the synergistic worlds of art and sound, exclusive access to celebrity events, music festival experiences, and atypical fashion.
- Assisted in event planning, invite coordination and gift basket preparation for Bella Magazine's Hampton's White Party hosted by British restaurateur and television personality, Lisa Vanderpump.
- Contributed to instagram growth as the magazine's "Street-Style" photographer; capturing the essence of New York street fashion
- Assisted stylist and photographer at the Nikki Hilton Cover shoot at the Roosevelt Hotel, NYC

Education

Tulane University

Bachelor of Arts - BA, Physical and Biological Anthropology, Fine Art,

Business · (2014 - 2018)

Flatiron School

UX/UI Design · (2019 - 2020)

University of Amsterdam

Social Sciences, Race & Physical Anthropology (2016)

Parsons School of Design - The New School

Graphic Design · (2013)

Washington University in St. Louis Communication Design · (2013)